Guide to the Student Christian Movement in New England Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
Student Christian Movement in New England Records
1926-1974
RG 57
Yale University Divinity School Library
21
(51 boxes)
The papers include correspondence, reports and minutes, study papers, printed material, and financial material. They constitute the official archive of the organization from its formation in 1934 to its dissolution in 1967. The papers contain information about the local Christian ministries' programs of various colleges and universities in New England. These papers fit into a line of documentation at YDSL of student work in New England, preceded by the Archives of the YMCA-Student Division and followed by the Archives of New England Commission for United Ministries in Higher Education. The Student Christian Movement was formed in 1934 by the YMCA, YWCA, and various Protestant denominations to promote cooperative religious work among college and university students in New England. In 1967, a reevaluation of the aims and future of the SCMNE resulted in a decision to change its name to University Christian Movement in New England and all member groups were to change their affiliation to the UCMNE.
Student Christian Movement in New England
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
The Student Christian Movement in New England was formed in 1934 as an agency designed to promote cooperative work among college and university students by various organizations and denominations. The policy of the Movement was to support the existing Christian groups on New England campuses rather than to create a new series of student units. The original participating organizations, the Y.M.C.A. and Y.W.C.A., were joined by the Congregational, Presbyterian and Methodist churches as "supporting" members and the Baptist, Lutheran, Episcopal, Unitarian and Disciples of Christ churches as "participating" members. In addition to coordinating Christian student work efforts on the New England campuses, the Student Christian Movement in New England also provided a link with national and worldwide organizations such as the National Intercollegiate Christian Council, the Fellowship of Reconciliation, the Student Volunteer Movement and the World's Student Christian Federation.
The Movement was governed by democratic councils which were representative of all constituent agencies and included student members. The S.C.M. staff had three main functions: 1) to visit and counsel local groups, 2) to teach, preach and provide resource information, and A) to interpret the purposes of the S.C.M. in New England and its relationship to wider university movements. The various conferences, meetings, and projects of the S.C.M. were designed to strengthen the Christian commitment of participating students and to provide opportunity for students to deal with the social problems of their time.
1965 and 1966 were designated as experimental years by the Student Christian Movement in New England, and many of its committees were restructured. The context of the organization changed in 1966 as a national University Christian Movement was formed to replace the National Student Christian Federation and the New England Commission for United Ministries in Higher Education began operation. (See Record Group No. 54 for papers of the New England Commission for United Ministries in Higher Education.) A new focus of S.C.M. activities was instituted in the fall of 1966 when "core groups" of students began to replace the S.C.M. staff as the means of providing counsel and information for local campus groups.
In January of 1967, the national Y.M.C.A. withdrew as a supporting member of the S.C.M. A period of reevaluation of the aims and future of the Student Christian Movement in New England resulted in a decision made at the 1967 Annual Representative Assembly that the name of the Movement be changed to the University Christian Movement in New England and that all member groups of the S.C.M. in New England become member groups of the U.C.M. in New England.
Scope and Contents
The papers provide valuable and relatively complete documentation of the changing format and concerns of Christian work among students in New England over a period of more than three decades. Each decade had its burning issues - the World War, civil rights, labor problems, the Vietnam war - and student response to the issues of their time is clearly evident both in the material produced by local college groups and in the programs of the S.C.M. as a whole. Extensive correspondence documents, for example, student involvement in civil rights work through donations of time and money to Southern causes and through the formation of the Northern Student Movement, which was designed to aid minorities in the North. Another long-term project of the Student Christian Movement in New England provided support for the oppressed Student Christian Movement of Brazil.
The S.C.M. in New England was not a highly centralized organization, and its archives came to the Library in no recognizable order. Detailed or sketchy records were kept, depending on the S.C.M. staff person maintaining the files. The first series, COMMITTEES, COMMISSIONS AND COUNCILS, includes material related to the administrative and policy-making units of the Student Christian Movement in New England. These committees generally had both adult and student membership and their names and number varied with the changing concerns of the Movement. The second series, COLLEGE FILES, reveals an interesting picture of the variation and relative strength or weakness of Christian groups on campuses throughout New England. The third series, CONFERENCES, contains information related to the various annual and one-time conferences and retreats which were perhaps the most vital activity of the S.C.M. in New England. Included in this series are the records of the Legislative Assembly, later known as the Annual Representative Assembly, which gathered delegates from all member campus groups to assess and plan the work of the Movement.
The fourth, fifth and sixth series provide the clearest documentation of the specific issues which involved the S.C.M. in New England during its years of existence. The RELATED GROUPS of Series VII refer to the various agencies and denominations which cooperated in the work of the S.C.M. Folders labeled "University Christian Movement" document the formation and early activities of the S.C.M.'s successor.
The papers of this record group are closely related to those of the Student Division of the Y.M.C.A. which are found in the Divinity Library's Record Group No. 58.
Arrangement
I. Committees, Commissions and Councils, 1930-1968
II. College Files, 1929-1969
III. Conferences, 1926-1977
IV. Program Materials, 1938-1966, n.d.
V. Historical Reports, 1934-1968
VI. Publications, 1934-1967
VII. Related Groups, 1930-1974
VIII. Financial Material, 1929-1969
College students -- Religious life; Universities and colleges -- Religion; Young Men's Christian Associations; Young Women's Christian associations; Youth in the ecumenical movement; Student Christian Movement in New England; YMCA of the USA; Young Women's Christian Association of the U.S.A
- Committees, Commissions, Councils, 1930-1968; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  The material in this series is organized alphabetically by the name of the committee, commission or council. Dates on the folder headings indicate when the committee was active. Name changes are not cross-referenced.
  - Alumni Committee, 1948-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Committee, 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administrative Committee, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Administrative Committee, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Administrative Committee, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees, 1964-1966, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brazil Commission, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brazil Commission, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Campus Relations Commission, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Christian Action Commission, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Christian Beliefs Commission, 1937-1947 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Christian Community Responsibility Commission, 1936-1947 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Christian Faith Commission, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Christian Outreach Commission, 1935-1939,n.d. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Church Commission, 1935-1948,n.d. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Civil Rights Commission, 1963-1965,n.d. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Commission on Faith and Function, 1934,1935,n.d. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Commission on International Concerns, 1964,1965,n.d. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Commission on Structure and Staff Deployment, 1963,n.d. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Committee on the Study of S.C.M. and Role of Sponsoring Agencies, 1958-1959,n.d. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Committee on the World Mission of the Church, 1949-1960,n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Committee on YMCA-SCM Relationship, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Community Relations and Labor Commission, 1938-1942,n.d. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Coordinating Committee for Student YMCA Work, 1961-1964,n.d. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Deputations Commission, 1939-1941,n.d. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Economics and Labor Commission, 1936,1941, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Ecumenical Commission, 1963-1965, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Executive Committee, 1934-1966, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Faculty Committee Finance Committee (see: Series VIII, Financial Material), 1941-1945,n.d. (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - General Committee, 1934,1935,n.d. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - General Committee, 1936,1937 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - General Committee, 1938,1939,n.d. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - General Committee, 1940,1941 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - General Committee, 1943-1947 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - General Committee, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - General Committee, 1950,1951 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - General Committee, 1952,1953 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - General Committee, 1967,n.d. (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Group Prejudice Commission, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Interfaith Resource Commission, 1939-1941, 1946,n.d. (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Interrace Commission, 1937-1942,n.d. (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Leadership Committee, 1934-1941 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Message Commission, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - National Commission on Leadership, 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Organization Commission, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Peace Commission, 1935-1965 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Personal Life and Relationships Commission, 1945-1948 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Personnel Committee, 1934-1955, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Personnel Committee, 1955-1963 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Personnel Committee, 1963-1968 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Policy Committee, 1935-1963 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Program- Commission, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Program Committee, 1948-1951 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Program Committee, 1951-1957 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Program and Leadership Committee, 1939-1948 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Promotion Commission, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Public Relations Committee, 1942-1959 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Regional Council, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Regional Council, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Regional Council, 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Regional Council, 1957-1959 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Regional Council, 1953-1956 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Regional Staff Council, 1965-1968 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Regional Staff Council, 1950-1966 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Religious Resources Commission, 1937-1942 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Revolution on Campus Commission, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Social Action Commission, 1936-1939 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Social Action Commission, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Special Co-m-mittee on Long Range Plan, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Staff and Finance Commission, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Staff and Finance Commission (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Staff Council, 1934-1938 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Staff Policy Committee, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Statement of Purpose Committee, 1945-1963 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Study and Survey Committee, 1947-1954 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - World Mission of the Church Commission, 1956-1960 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - World Refugee Year Committee, 1959-1962 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - World Relatedness Commission, 1943-1948 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Worship and Cell Group Committee, 1942-1947 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Worship Commission, 1938-1940 (Box 7, Folder 80)
- College Files, 1929-1969; Series II
  The material in Series II is primarily arranged alphabetically by the name of the college or university. Within the material for each educational institution correspondence appears first' followed by reports; and finally by program material produced by the local student group. Following the material organized by institution are
  1) material related to individual local church student groups and
  2) reports to Y.M.C.A. headquarters from miscellaneous student groups.
  - American International College, 1956-1964 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Amherst College Correspondence, 1947-1965 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Amherst College Reports, 1943-1963 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Amherst College Program materials (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Aroostook State Teachers College, 1947-1962 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Back Bay and Fenway Campus Ministry, 1961-1963 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Bangor Theological Seminary, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Bates College Correspondence, 1947-1964 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Bates College Reports, 1946-1964 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Bates College Program materials (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Berkshire Community College, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Boston State Teachers College, 1955-1956,1965 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Boston University Correspondence, 1947-1961 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Boston University Reports, 1951-1958 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Boston University Reports, 1959-1963 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Boston University Program materials (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Boston University Program materials (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Bowdoin College, 1939-1965 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Bradford Junior College, 1938,1944-1945,1964 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Brandeis University, 1952-1963 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - University of Bridgeport, 1952-1953,1963 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Bridgewater State College, 1962-1967 (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - Brown University Correspondence, 1947,1964 (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - Brown University Reports, 1939-1965 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - Brown University Program Materials (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - Bryant College, 1948-1962 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - Castleton State Teachers College, 1952-1965 (Box 9, Folder 107)
  - Central Connecticut State College, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 108)
  - Clark University, 1929,1943-1948,1962 (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - Colby College Correspondence, 1952-1965 (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - Colby College Reports, 1947-1963 (Box 9, Folder 111)
  - Colby College Program Materials (Box 9, Folder 112)
  - Colby Junior College, 1941-1964 (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - Connecticut College for Women, 1943-1958,1966 (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Connecticut colleges (Box 9, Folder 115)
  - University of Connecticut, Storrs Correspondence, 1947-1966 (Box 10, Folder 116)
  - University of Connecticut, Storrs Reports, 1934,1940-1955 (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - University of Connecticut, Storrs Reports, 1956-1963 (Box 10, Folder 118)
  - University of Connecticut, Storrs Reports, 1963-1967 (Box 10, Folder 119)
  - University of Connecticut, Storrs Program Materials (Box 10, Folder 120)
  - University of Connecticut, Storrs Program Materials (Box 10, Folder 121)
  - University of Connecticut, Waterbury, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 122)
  - Danbury State College, 1952-1966 (Box 10, Folder 123)
  - Dartmouth College Correspondence, 1954-1967 (Box 10, Folder 124)
  - Dartmouth College Reports, 1946-1963 (Box 10, Folder 125)
  - Dartmouth College Program Materials (Box 10, Folder 126)
  - Dean Junior College, 1952-1962 (Box 10, Folder 127)
  - Emerson College, 1952-1961 (Box 10, Folder 128)
  - Endicott Junior College, 1941-1956 (Box 10, Folder 129)
  - Farmington State Teachers College, 1943-1966 (Box 11, Folder 130)
  - Fitchburg State Teachers College, 1948-1965 (Box 11, Folder 131)
  - Framingham State Teachers College, 1951-1963 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - Gorham State Teachers College, 1947-1964 (Box 11, Folder 133)
  - Greater Hartford Campus Ministry Correspondence, 1963-1968 (Box 11, Folder 134)
  - Greater Hartford Campus Ministry Reports, minutes, 1963-1966 (Box 11, Folder 135)
  - Greater Hartford Campus Ministry Program materials (Box 11, Folder 136)
  - Green Mountain Junior College, 1946-1956 (Box 11, Folder 137)
  - Hartford Canterbury Association, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 138)
  - Hartford College Fellowship Correspondence, 1955-1960 (Box 11, Folder 139)
  - Hartford College Fellowship Program Materials (Box 11, Folder 140)
  - Hartford Seminary Foundation, 1953-1968 (Box 11, Folder 141)
  - University of Hartford, 1965,1966 (Box 11, Folder 142)
  - Harvard Medical School, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 143)
  - Harvard University, 1942-1961 (Box 12, Folder 144)
  - Harvard University, Baptist Work, 1957-1965 (Box 12, Folder 145)
  - Harvard University, Congregational and Presbyterian work, 1956-1965 (Box 12, Folder 146)
  - Harvard University, Episcopal Church at Harvard and Radcliffe, 1956-1961 (Box 12, Folder 147)
  - Harvard University, Memorial Church, 1961-1964 (Box 12, Folder 148)
  - Harvard University, Methodist work, 1946-1960 (Box 12, Folder 149)
  - Johnson State Teachers College, 1952-1958 (Box 12, Folder 150)
  - Keene, N.H. - Congregational Young Adult Group, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 151)
  - Keene Teachers College, 1947-1962 (Box 12, Folder 152)
  - Lasell Junior College, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 153)
  - Lesley College, 1951-1959 (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - Lowell, Mass. - Iona Fellowship, 1952-1963 (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - Lyndon State Teachers College, 1952-1960 (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - Maine colleges, 1946-1947 (Box 12, Folder 157)
  - University of Maine, Brunswick, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 158)
  - University of Maine, Orono. Correspondence, 1946-1950 (Box 12, Folder 159)
  - University of Maine, Orono Correspondence, 1951-1964 (Box 12, Folder 160)
  - University of Maine, Orono Reports, 1942-1950 (Box 12, Folder 161)
  - University of Maine, Orono Reports, 1951-1965 (Box 12, Folder 162)
  - University of Maine, Orono Program materials (Box 12, Folder 163)
  - University of Maine, Portland, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 164)
  - Marblehead, Ma. - Old North Church Christian Association, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 165)
  - Marlboro College, 1963-1969 (Box 13, Folder 166)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 13, Folder 167)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology Reports, 1944-1956 (Box 13, Folder 168)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology Program Materials (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Massachusetts State College, 1946-1947 (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - University of Massachusetts Correspondence, 1947-1967 (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - University of Massachusetts Reports, 1946-1959 (Box 13, Folder 172)
  - University of Massachusetts Reports, 1960-1967 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - University of Massachusetts Program materials (Box 13, Folder 174)
  - Middlebury College, 1941-1966 (Box 13, Folder 175)
  - Mitchell Junior College, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 176)
  - Mount Holyoke College Correspondence, 1946-1965 (Box 14, Folder 177)
  - Mount Holyoke College Reports, 1935-1962 (Box 14, Folder 178)
  - Mount Holyoke College Program materials (Box 14, Folder 179)
  - Nasson College, 1941-1963 (Box 14, Folder 180)
  - New England Baptist Hospital School of Nursing, 1953-1954 (Box 14, Folder 181)
  - New England College, 1955-1965 (Box 14, Folder 182)
  - New Hampshire colleges, 1946-1947,n.d. (Box 14, Folder 183)
  - University of New Hampshire Correspondence, 1944-1963 (Box 14, Folder 184)
  - University of New Hampshire Reports, 1943-1955 (Box 14, Folder 185)
  - University of New Hampshire Reports, 1956-1959 (Box 14, Folder 186)
  - University of New Hampshire Reports, 1960-1968 (Box 14, Folder 187)
  - University of New Hampshire Program materials (Box 14, Folder 188)
  - University of New Hampshire Program materials (Box 14, Folder 189)
  - New Haven State Teachers College, 1947-1952 (Box 15, Folder 190)
  - Nichols College, 1961-1963 (Box 15, Folder 191)
  - North Adams State College, 1952-1964 (Box 15, Folder 192)
  - Northeastern University, 1942-1954 (Box 15, Folder 193)
  - Norwalk Community College, 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 194)
  - Norwich University, Northfield? Vt., 1951-1960 (Box 15, Folder 195)
  - Pembroke College Reports, 1947-1958 (Box 15, Folder 196)
  - Pembroke College Program materials (Box 15, Folder 197)
  - Pine Manor Junior College, 1953-1955 (Box 15, Folder 198)
  - Plymouth State Teachers College, 1945-1957 (Box 15, Folder 199)
  - Quinnipiac College, 1959-1963 (Box 15, Folder 200)
  - Rhode Island colleges, 1947-1962 (Box 15, Folder 201)
  - Rhode Island College, 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 202)
  - Rhode Island College of Education, 1953-1959 (Box 15, Folder 203)
  - Rhode Island School of Nursing, 1947-1949 (Box 15, Folder 204)
  - University of Rhode Island Correspondence, 1946-1963 (Box 15, Folder 205)
  - University of Rhode Island Reports, minutes, 1941-1956 (Box 15, Folder 206)
  - University of Rhode Island Reports, minutes, 1957-1959 (Box 15, Folder 207)
  - University of Rhode Island Reports, minutes, 1960-1962 (Box 15, Folder 208)
  - University of Rhode Island Reports, minutes, 1963-1967 (Box 16, Folder 209)
  - University of Rhode Island Program materials (Box 16, Folder 210)
  - Ricker College, 1950-1962 (Box 16, Folder 211)
  - Salem Teachers College, 1953-1965 (Box 16, Folder 212)
  - Simmons College, 1946-1961 (Box 16, Folder 213)
  - Smith College Correspondence, 1954-1969 (Box 16, Folder 214)
  - Smith College Reports, 1940-1962 (Box 16, Folder 215)
  - Smith College Program materials (Box 16, Folder 216)
  - Springfield College, 1947-1964 (Box 16, Folder 217)
  - Stevens College, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 218)
  - Suffolk University, 1961-1963 (Box 16, Folder 219)
  - Trinity College, 1947-1959 (Box 16, Folder 220)
  - Tufts University, 1952-1966 (Box 16, Folder 221)
  - University Lutheran Association of Greater Boston, 1948,1957-1962 (Box 16, Folder 222)
  - Vermont colleges, 1947-1948,1966 (Box 16, Folder 223)
  - Vermont Junior College Correspondence, 1947-1960 (Box 16, Folder 224)
  - Vermont Junior College Reports, 1950-1961 (Box 16, Folder 225)
  - Vermont Junior College Program materials (Box 16, Folder 226)
  - Vermont - State Y.W.C.A. (Box 16, Folder 227)
  - University of Vermont Correspondence, 1946-1965 (Box 17, Folder 228)
  - University of Vermont Reports, 1946-1963 (Box 17, Folder 229)
  - University of Vermont Program materials (Box 17, Folder 230)
  - Washington State Teachers College, Machias, Maine, 1945-1963 (Box 17, Folder 231)
  - Wellesley College Correspondence, 1946-1963 (Box 17, Folder 232)
  - Wellesley College Reports, 1947-1962 (Box 17, Folder 233)
  - Wellesley College Program materials (Box 17, Folder 234)
  - Wesleyan University, 1946-1965 (Box 17, Folder 235)
  - Westbrook Junior College, 1947-1953 (Box 17, Folder 236)
  - Westfield State College, 1958-1961 (Box 17, Folder 237)
  - Wheaton College (Box 17, Folder 238)
  - Wheelock College, 1943,1946 (Box 17, Folder 239)
  - Williams College, 1947-1965 (Box 17, Folder 240)
  - Willimantic State Teachers College, 1953-1954 (Box 17, Folder 241)
  - Worcester Campus Ministry, 1957-1966 (Box 17, Folder 242)
  - Worcester Junior College, 1957,1963 (Box 17, Folder 243)
  - Worcester Polytechnic Institute Correspondence, 1945-1957 (Box 18, Folder 244)
  - Worcester Polytechnic Institute Reports, 1944-1960 (Box 18, Folder 245)
  - Worcester State Teachers College, 1944-1963 (Box 18, Folder 246)
  - Yale University Correspondence, 1945-1963 (Box 18, Folder 247)